The second main data structure in Pandas is a DataFrame,
Pandas 的第二种主要数据结构为 DataFrame
which is a two-dimensional object with labeled rows and
DataFrame 是一个二维对象 其行与列都有标签
columns and can also hold multiple data types.
也可以存放多种数据类型
If you're familiar with Excel,
如果你熟悉 Excel 的话
you can think of a DataFrame as a really powerful spreadsheet.
你可以把 DataFrame 想成一个十分强大的电子表格
We can create Pandas DataFrames manually or by loading data from a file.
我们可以手动创建 Pandas DataFrame 也可以从文件中把数据加载进来
We will start by creating a DataFrame manually from a dictionary,
我们先讲怎么用包含多个 Pandas 序列的字典
containing several pandas series.
手动创建 DataFrame
Let's create that dictionary and then pass it into Pandas DataFrame function.
首先 创建字典 然后将字典传递给 Pandas 的函数 DataFrame
Here's one that contains the shopping carts of two people,
这个字典包含了 Alice 和 Bob 两人
Alice and Bob on an online store.
在某个网上商店里的购物车
Each series contains the price of the items and is labeled with the item names.
每个序列都含有物品价格和物品名标签
And let's confirm the items is of the datatype dictionary.
现在确认一下 items 的数据类型是字典
Now that we have a dictionary,
创建好字典
we are ready to create a DataFrame by passing it to the DataFrame function.
就可以把字典传递给函数 DataFrame 从而生成 DataFrame 了
Remember, when using the DataFrame function,
记住 使用函数 DataFrame 时
capitalize the D and F in DataFrame.
D 和 F 都要大写
There are several things to notice here.
这里需要注意几点
First, we see that DataFrames are displayed in a tabular form,
第一 我们可以看到 这个 DataFrame 是以表格的形式呈现的
much like a spreadsheet with the labels of the rows and columns in bold.
它很像一张电子表格 其中行与列的标签加粗了
Also notice that the row labels of the DataFrame are built from
第二 DataFrame 的行标签
the union of the index labels we provided in the series,
取自各序列的索引标签
and the column labels of the DataFrame are taken from the keys of the dictionary.
DataFrame 的列标签则取自字典的键
The columns are arranged alphabetically and not in the order given by the dictionary.
列以字母顺序排列 而不是字典给出的顺序
Later, we will see that this is not the case
稍后我们会看到
when we load data into a DataFrame from a file.
如果从文件里把数据载入 DataFrame 情况就不是如此了
Lastly, notice the NaN values that appeared in a DataFrame.
最后 注意 DataFrame 里的 NaN 值
NaN stands for not a number,
NaN 的意思是非数字
and is Pandas way of indicating that it doesn't have
Pandas 用 NaN 来表示
a value for this particular row and index.
某索引下的某一行没有值
For example, if we look at the column Alice,
比如 Alice 这一列
we see that it has NaN in the watch index.
我们可以发现索引 watch 处为 NaN
This is because the dictionary over here didn't have an item for Alice called watch.
因为字典的 Alice 序列没有一个叫 watch 的项
Whenever a DataFrame is created,
在创建 DataFrame 时
if a particular column doesn't have values for a particular index,
只要某一列的某个索引没有值
Pandas will put a NaN there.
Pandas 就会在该处放置一个 NaN
If we were to feed this data into a machine-learning algorithm,
如果我们要把这些数据输入到机器学习算法中
we would have to remove these NaN values first.
那就得先把 NaN 值移除
In a later video,
稍后的视频
we will learn how to deal with Nan values and clean our data.
会讲解怎么处理 NaN 值并清理数据
For now, we will leave these values in our dataframe.
现在我们先不管 DataFrame 里的这些值
In this example, we created a Pandas DataFrame from
在上述例子中 我们用字典创建了一个 Pandas DataFrame
a dictionary of pandas series that had clearly defined index labels.
其中 字典由 Pandas 序列组成 序列有明确的索引标签
If we don't provide index labels however,
但如果我们不提供索引标签
Pandas will use numerical row indices when it creates the DataFrame.
在创建 DataFrame 时 Pandas 就会用数字行索引
Let's create the same dictionary without the index labels.
我们用同样的数据来创建一个不带索引标签的字典
We can see that pandas indexes the rows of the DataFrame starting from zero,
可以看到 Pandas 为 DataFrame 建立的行索引是从 0 开始的
just like NumPy indexes its arrays.
就像 NumPy 为其数组建立的索引一样
Like we did with the pandas series,
和 Pandas 序列一样
we can also extract information from a DataFrame using attributes.
我们也可以用属性从 DataFrame 中提取信息
Let's print some information on our shopping carts DataFrame from earlier.
我们来输出刚才那个 DataFrame shopping_carts 中的一些信息
We can get the index labels,
我们可以用这些属性从 DataFrame 中获取索引标签
column labels and data from our dataframe with these attributes,
列标签和数据
and we can use the same attributes to get information about its shape.
我们还可以用同样的属性来获取 DataFrame 的形状信息
This dataframe has two dimensions with five rows and two columns,
这个 DataFrame 有两个维度 共有五行两列
making a total size of 10.
总大小为 10
When creating the shopping carts DataFrame,
在创建 DataFrame shopping_carts 时
we pass the whole items dictionary to the DataFrame function.
我们把整个字典 items 传递给了函数 DataFrame
However, there might be cases where you're only interested in a subset of the data.
但有时候你只对数据的某一部分感兴趣
Pandas let's us select which data we want to put in
Pandas 允许我们选择要放入 DataFrame 的数据部分
our DataFrame with the keywords, column and index.
要实现该操作 我们可以用关键字 columns 和 index
Let's see some examples.
来看些例子
Here's a DataFrame that only loads Bob's shopping cart,
这是只加载了 Bob 购物车的 DataFrame
and here's one that only has selected items for both Alice and Bob.
而这只选出了 Alice 和 Bob 的一些物品
And this is one that only has selected items from Alice's shopping cart.
这个只从 Alice 购物车中选出了部分物品
You can also manually create DataFrames from a dictionary of lists or arrays.
你还可以手动用列表或数组字典创建 DataFrame
The procedure is the same as before,
操作和之前一样
we start by creating the dictionary and then pass it into the DataFrame function.
先创建字典 然后将字典传递给函数 DataFrame
In this case however,
但是
all the lists or arrays in a dictionary must be of the same length.
字典里的所有列表或数组长度必须相同
Here's a dictionary of integers and floats.
这个字典里的数据是整数和浮点数
Notice that since the data dictionary we created doesn't have index labels,
注意 由于我们创建的数据字典没有索引标签
Pandas automatically uses numerical row indices when it creates the DataFrame.
Pandas 在创建 DataFrame 时 会自动使用数字行索引
We can however add these labels by using the index keyword in the DataFrame function.
但我们也可以在函数 DataFrame 里用关键字 index 来添加标签
The last method we'll look at for manually creating
最后一个手动创建 Pandas DataFrame 的方法
Pandas DataFrames is using a list of Python dictionaries.
是输入一个 Python 字典列表
Here's an example, again we don't have index labels.
来看这个例子 这里还是没有索引标签
So Panda put numerical row indices here,
所以 Pnadas 会把数字行索引放这儿
and let's assume we're going to use this DataFrame.
假设我们要用这个 DataFrame
to hold the number of items a particular store has in stock.
来存放某家商店的货物库存量
We'll rename the index labels to store 1 store 2.
将索引标签重命名为 store 1 和 store 2